A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 11775-13948 FA739E
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Les correlation entre la pluviometerie, les paturages, et la production animale (Reports 012329-059), 1974 (Box 601)
- Summary of the research on controlling weeds in Algeria. (Reports 012329-060), 1974 (Box 601)
- Wheat production under low rainfall conditions in Algeria (Reports 012329-061), 1974 (Box 601)
- Production research report for regions of Algiers, el Asnam, Medea and Tizi Ouzou (Reports 012329-062), 1974 (Box 601)
- Algerian status report for cereal research and production, crop years 1972-1974. (Reports 012329-063) (Box 601)
- Expose sommaire sur la recherche et la production cerealieres en Algerie (Reports 012329-064), 1974 (Box 601)
- Annual report CIMMYT-I.D.G.C., 1974-1975: Algeria (Reports 012329-065) (Box 601)
- CIMMYT annual report: Algeria 1974-1975 / International Maize and Wheat Improvement Center (CIMMYT). (Reports 012329-066) (Box 601)
- CIMMYT narrative report, October 1, 1973 - September 30, 1975: Support of wheat production program in North Africa /International Maize and Wheat Improvement Center (CIMMYT) (Reports 012329-067) (Box 601)
- CIMMYT progress report: Tunisia (Reports 012329-068), 1974-1975 (Box 601)
- Programme de recherche de la section experimentation - CIMMYT (Reports 012329-069), 1974-1975 (Box 601)
- Weed control program (1974-1975) of the Cooperative Cereal Project of the Government of Tunisia, CIMMYT, and the Ford Foundation. (Reports 012329-070) (Box 601)
- USAID final reports (Cereals project, USAID, CIMMYT, Ford Foundation) (Reports 012329-071), 1974-1975 (Box 601)
  United States. Agency for International Development
- CIMMYT review of the Tunisian and Algerian cereal programs (Reports 012329-072), 1975 (Box 601)
- The introduction of an annual forage legume-crop rotation system in Tunisia (Reports 012329-073), undated (Box 601)
- The introduction of a medi-crop rotation system (Reports 012329-074), undated (Box 601)
- Review of wheat project (Reports 012329-075), undated (Box 601)
- The CIMMYT seed production and technology activity: Tunisia and Algeria, 1973 (Reports 012329-076), 1973-1975 (Box 601)
- Essential components of seed industries: Examples of successfully implmented activities: Seed production. (Reports 012329-077), undated (Box 601)
- A review of progress in the Tunisian-North African seed program, November 1974 (Reports 012329-078), 1975 (Box 601)
- Review - Program for the experimentation section (Reports 012329-079), undated (Box 601)
- Past progress, present status and future needs of the Algerian cereal program (Reports 012329-080), 1975 (Box 601)
- Status report on the wheat production program in North Africa - Some facts and issues - Algeria (Reports 012329-081), 1975 (Box 602)
- Status report on the wheat production program in North Africa - Some facts and issues - Tunisia (Reports 012329-082), 1975 (Box 602)
- Report on the review committee on development of the plan for the IDGC (Institut de Development des Grandes Cultures). (Reports 012329-083), 1975 (Box 602)
- An evaluation of the cereal project in Tunisia and in Algeria and the related Ford Foundation grants to CIMMYT (06800848) (Reports 012329-084), 1975 (Box 602)
- Green revolution: The Tunisian experience Thesis submitted to the University of Minnesota (Reports 012329-085), 1975 (Box 602)
- Algerian seed program: A review of some recent developments and suggestions, November 17-23 (Reports 012329-086), 1975 (Box 602)
- Report on visits to seed technology centers (Reports 012329-087), 1975 (Box 602)
- Report on the FAO expert consultation on seed industry development (Reports 012329-088), 1975 (Box 602)
- Annual report (I.D.G.C. - CIMMYT): Algeria. (Reports 012329-089), 1975-1976 (Box 602)
- CIMMYT: Annual narrative report: October 1975-September 1976, and final narrative report - training through December 1976. (Reports 012329-090) (Box 602)
- CIMMYT progress report: Tunisia (Reports 012329-091), 1975-1976 (Box 602)
- Green revolution: The Tunisian experience (Abridged by CIMMYT) (Reports 012329-092), 1976 (Box 602)
- Confidential report on the Tunisian cereal program (Reports 012329-093), 1976 (Box 602)
- USAID report: Review of achievment of accelerated cereals production project (Reports 012329-094), 1976 (Box 602)
- CIMMYT/Algeria proposed program, 1977 (Reports 012329-095), 1976 (Box 602)
- Proposed work for contract period 1977-1979. (Reports 012329-096) (Box 602)
- Report on the Egyptian seed program. (Reports 012329-097), undated (Box 602)
- A review of progress in the Tunisian - North American seed program, August 1975 - February 1976. (Reports 012329-098) (Box 602)
- Report on present and future needs of seed production in Tunisia (Reports 012329-099), 1976 (Box 602)
- Algerian trip report (Reports 012329-100), 1976 (Box 602)
- CIMMYT and the cereal program in Algeria (Reports 012329-101), 1976 (Box 602)
- Supplement to the report on the T.A.C. Quinquennial review of CIMMYT (Reports 012329-102), 1976 (Box 602)
- Foundation grants to CIMMYT - Preparation for T.A.C. review (Reports 012329-103), 1976 (Box 602)
- Tunisian cereal project, paper prepared August 1976 for T.A.C. Review Committee (Reports 012329-104) (Box 602)
- Systemes de production et comportements des agriculteurs: Cas d'une region dans le nord de la Tunisie. (Reports 012329-105), 1976 (Box 602)
- CIMMYT Report on wheat improvement (Reports 012329-106), 1976 (Box 602)
- Memos and draft re: agricultural policy and politics in Tunisia, 1962 (Reports 012329-107), 1976 (Box 603)
- CIMMYT report: Medicago research and observations in 1975 (Reports 012329-108), 1976 (Box 603)
- Annual report: CIMMYT-I.D.G.C., 1976-1977: Algeria (Reports 012329-109) (Box 603)
- CIMMYT annual narrative report, October 1976 - September 1977: Support of the wheat production program in North Africa (Reports 012329-110) (Box 603)
- CIMMYT and the cereal program in Algeria (Reports 012329-111), 1977 (Box 603)
- The Ford Foundation/CIMMYT cereal program in Algeria: A reivew submitted to the Ford Foundation (Reports 012329-112), 1977 (Box 603)
- The Ford Foundation/CIMMYT cereal program in Tunisia: A review report submitted to the Ford Foundation (Reports 012329-113), 1977 (Box 603)
- A report on Algerian wheat production prepared by CIMMYT and collaborators (Reports 012329-114), 1978 (Box 603)
- Cultural and weed control: Practices for barley production in North Africa (Reports 012329-115), 1977 (Box 603)
- Development of crop rotation technology for Tunisia (Reports 012329-116), 1978 (Box 603)
- Developpment d'une technologie pour la production cerealiere en Tunisie (Reports 012329-117), 1977 (Box 603)
- June 1977 field trip to Tunisia (Reports 012329-118) (Box 603)
- Adoption of unlike high yielding varieties in Tunisia (Reports 012329-119), undated (Box 603)
- June 1977 field trip to Algeria (Reports 012329-120) (Box 603)
- Management for increased sheat production in Algeria (Reports 012329-121), 1978 (Box 603)
- Rapport sur la production Algerienne de ble (Reports 012329-122), 1978 (Box 603)
- Report on Tunisian wheat production (Reports 012329-123), 1978 (Box 603)
- Medicago and the wheat-medicago rotation in Algeria (Reports 012329-124), 1978 (Box 604)
- Cerealiculture: revue trimestriel scientifique et technique d'information (Reports 012329-125), 1979 (Box 604)
  L'Institut de Developpment des Grandes Cultures
- Situation des cereales en Algerie (Reports 012329-126), 1979 (Box 604)
- Conjoncture agricole, enquete de Decembre (Reports 012329-127), 1977 (Box 604)
  Tunisia. Wizārat al-Filāḥah
- Enquete agricole de base (Reports 012329-128), 1977 (Box 604)
- Semidwarf bread wheats: names, parentage, pedigrees, origin (Reports 012329-129), 1977 (Box 604)
- Le ble: Erreur d'allocation et risque: Tunisie du nord (Reports 012329-130), 1980 (Box 604)
- Final report: Medicago research, 1978 (Reports 012329-131), 1979 (Box 604)
- Notes sur les problemes de formation pour le developpment de l'artisanat Tunisien (Reports 012329-132), 1962 (Box 604)
- Some data on agriculture and its dual character in the Maghreb. (Reports 012329-133), 1962 (Box 604)
- A mediterranean center to aid in small-medium industry development (Reports 012329-134), 1962 (Box 604)
- Agricultural policy in former French North Africa (Reports 012329-135), 1964 (Box 604)
- Man power training in Tunisia (Reports 012329-136), 1964 (Box 604)
- Report of activities and progress; Algeria vital statistics project: (Reports 012329-137), 1965 (Box 604)
- Cours practique d'Anglais (Reports 012329-138), 1965 (Box 604)
- A study of the public employment service in Tunisia. (Reports 012329-139), 1965 (Box 604)
- Une etude du service d'emploi public de la Tunisie. (Reports 012329-140), 1965 (Box 604)
- A progress report on Algerian vital statistics project, October 1965 (Reports 012329-141), 1966 (Box 604)
- Un rapport de progres sur le programme d'etat-civil Algerien, Octobre 1965 - Decembre (Reports 012329-142), 1966 (Box 604)
- Notes sur les methodes statistiques en demographie et d'etat civil (Reports 012329-143), 1966 (Box 604)
- Report and evaluation of statistical and reporting procedures in the Fonction Publique, Ministry of Interior, Algeria (Reports 012329-144), 1966 (Box 604)
- Tunisia's experiment in family planning (Reports 012329-145), 1966 (Box 604)
- Program for accelerating private foreign investment in the less developmed countries (Reports 012329-146), 1966 (Box 604)
- O.D. Overseas Development self study: Tunisia, Morocco, Algeria (Reports 012329-147), 1966 (Box 605)
- Etude preliminaire sur la reforme administrative en Algerie (Reports 012329-148), 1966 (Box 605)
- Utilization of the graduates from technical and vocational training institutes in Tunisia (Reports 012329-149), 1966 (Box 605)
- Ecole Nationale d'Administration: proposals for increased effectiveness (Reports 012329-150), 1966 (Box 605)
- Enquete sur la tiuation d'un enhantillon d'anciens eleves diplomes (Reports 012329-151), 1966 (Box 605)
- Le Journal de Medecine du Maroc: Revista medica de marruecos, vol. 3, no. 1. (Reports 012329-152), 1967 (Box 605)
- How to establish a company in Tunisia: Administrative and legal procedures (Reports 012329-153), 1967 (Box 605)
  Centre de Promotion des Investmnets (Tunis, Tunisia)
- La formation d'une entreprise en Tunisie: Procedures administratives et juridiques (Reports 012329-154), 1967 (Box 605)
- Specimen du statut d'une societe anonyme (S.A.) (Reports 012329-155), 1967 (Box 605)
  Centre de Promotion des Investmnets (Tunis, Tunisia).
- Specimen du statut d'une societe a responsibilite limitee (Reports 012329-156), 1967 (Box 605)
- Report to the government of Morocco on Family Planning in Morocco (Reports 012329-157), 1967 (Box 605)
- Personnel administration for emerging countries (Reports 012329-158), 1967 (Box 605)
- Administration publique et organisation et methode (Reports 012329-159), 1967 (Box 605)
- The 1967 summer seminar in Mahdia, Tunisia: Report and recommendations (Reports 012329-160) (Box 605)
- Preparation du plan de developpment 1968 (Reports 012329-161), 1967 (Box 605)
  Morocco
- A short bibliography of books currently in print relative to the Maghreb. (Reports 012329-162), 1967 (Box 605)
- Enquete nationale demographique (Reports 012329-163), 1967 (Box 605)
- Second English seminar, summer 1968, Mahdia, Tunisia. (Reports 012329-164) (Box 605)
- Tunisia's experience in family planning Reprint from the journal 'Demography' vol. 5, no. 2 (Reports 012329-165), 1968 (Box 605)
- Ecole Nationale d'Administration: The library (Reports 012329-166), 1968 (Box 605)
- Ecole Nationale d'Administration: La Bibliotheque (Reports 012329-167), 1968 (Box 605)
- Enquete nationale demographique: Resultats provisoires (Reports 012329-168), 1968 (Box 605)
- Enquete nationale demographique: Resultats provisoires: Annexes I-IV (Reports 012329-169), 1968 (Box 605)
- Enquete nationale demographique: Resultats provisoires: Annexes V-VIII (Reports 012329-170), 1968 (Box 605)
- Place du planning familial dans l'evoluttion recente de la natalite en Tunisie (Reports 012329-171), 1968 (Box 606)
- Seminaire de demographie, 1967-1968: Resultats d'une experience (Reports 012329-172) (Box 606)
- Mission for the analysis of the project for the organization and development of truck farming in Tunisia (Reports 012329-173), 1969 (Box 606)
- Reunion du 27 Mars 1969: David Heaps and 'Les Chefs de Projet du Fonds Special (Reports 012329-174) (Box 606)
- Tunisian wheat production problems and suggestions for increasing yields and production (Reports 012329-175), 1966 (Box 606)
- 1969 Summer seminar for teachers of English, Carthage, Tunisia. (Reports 012329-176) (Box 606)
- Reconstitution of the University's library, University of Algiers: Final report (Reports 012329-177), 1969 (Box 606)
- Demographie - Tunisie Demography - Tunisia: Rapport de fin de mission, Mai 1967 - Septembre (Reports 012329-178), 1969 (Box 606)
- La bibliotheque: Juin 1967 - Septembre 1969 (Rapport d'activitie (Reports 012329-179) (Box 606)
- An experience in the introduction of sex education material into a school system, Spring (Reports 012329-180), 1969 (Box 606)
- Tunisian education for business management and public administration (Reports 012329-181), 1968 (Box 606)
- Rapport sur le developpment et l'organisation des cultures maraicheres en Tunisie (Reports 012329-182), 1969 (Box 606)
- Rapport de M. B.G. Moussouros sur l'enseignement professionnel dans l'agriculture et la formation des cadres (Reports 012329-183), 1970 (Box 606)
- Notes sur les perspecitives de la planification en Tunisie (Reports 012329-184), 1970 (Box 606)
- Une methode de planification de la main-d'oeuvre: Rapport annexe (Reports 012329-185), 1970 (Box 606)
- Notes on the direction of future Tunisian planning and possible planning assistance (Reports 012329-186), 1970 (Box 606)
- Summary of interviews held between June 3 and July 14, 1970 in connection with a study of the direction of future Tunisian planning (Reports 012329-187) (Box 606)
- An approach to manpower planning (Reports 012329-188), 1970 (Box 606)
- Les normes de fonctionnment des entreprises et des secteurs industriels.. De la Tunisie (Reports 012329-189), 1970 (Box 606)
- La valorisation par l'entreprise des ressources humaines (Reports 012329-190), 1969 (Box 606)
- Vocational agricultural education in Tunisia and the training of intermediate agricultural cadres (Reports 012329-191), 1970 (Box 606)
- Tunisia training rationalization project, December 27, 1968 - January 3 (Reports 012329-192), 1971 (Box 606)
- Projet: Bourse de sous-traitance (Reports 012329-193), 1970 (Box 606)
- Projet de formation pedagogique des professeurs de l'enseignement secondaire agricole (Reports 012329-194), 1970 (Box 606)
- Le development du 'Management' en Algerie (Reports 012329-195), 1971 (Box 606)
- Aspects geographiques, agricoles et socio-economique de governorat de medenine (Reports 012329-196), 1976 (Box 606)
- Proposed dairying employment program in Egypt 1982? (Reports 012330) (Box 607)
  Memorandum to John Gerhart and Cynthia Myntti. Briefly summarizes issues proposed by Cairo field office to initiate a program to improve low-income women's employment in dairying production and processing.
  Rural women -- Employment -- Egypt; Women in development -- Egypt; Poor women -- Employment -- Egypt; Dairying -- Economic aspects -- Egypt; Ford Foundation. Field Office Cairo; Ford Foundation Program development Egypt
- Final external review of eleven grants to epidemiology institutions in Indonesia: review carried out August 6 - September 1, 1992 (Reports 012331) (Box 607)
  Review carried out "to assess the general impact of Ford Foundation support to epidemiological training and research institutions in Indonesia" and "to prepare final external reports on each of eleven institutional grants ..." -p. 6
  Asia/Southeast Asia; Urban Poverty program
  08800279;870-0712;840-0132;880-0278;880-0280;890-0332;870-0714;890-0273;870-0131;890-0266;870-0713.
  Epidemiology -- Research -- Indonesia; Gadjah Mada University (Indonesia) GAMA Evaluation; Udayana University (Indonesia) Evaluation; University of Indonesia UI Evaluation; Atmajaya University (Indonesia) Evaluation; Indonesia. Departemen Kesehatan Evaluation.
- Lagos program proposals: 1982-1983 assistance to the governmental and non-governmental service delivery systems, 1981 Dec. (Reports 012332) (Box 607)
  Memorandum to Dr. Tyler Biggs.
  Non-governmental organizations -- Africa, West; Rural development -- Study and teaching -- Africa, West; Urban renewal -- Study and teaching -- Africa, West; Ford Foundation. Field office Lagos; Ford Foundation. Rural Poverty and Resources; Ford Foundation. Urban Poverty; Ford Foundation Program development Africa, West
- Report of Egyptian trip on law and status of women and reproductive health, May 12-20 (Reports 012333), 1990 (Box 607)
  "The purpose of this trip was to explore ways of developing programming in the area of law and status of women and reproductive health, focusing in particular on Egypt." -p. 1 of report. Includes a 5-page memorandum from Sandy Lane and Emma Playfair respo
  Rights and Social Justice
  5, 19, 7, 3 leaves.
  Women's health services -- Egypt; Women's rights -- Egypt; Ford Foundation. Rights and Social Justice; Ford Foundation Program development Egypt
- Problems of citizenship in Brazil: civil rights, human rights, and judicial reform (Reports 012334), 1992 (Box 607)
  Report, written for the Rio de Janeiro field office, evaluates two areas which have not kept pace with the consolidation of democracy in Brazil: the expansion of citizenship rights and the reform of the judiciary. In this context, Holston looks at legal s
  Latin America and the Caribbean/Brazil;Rights and Social Justice
  Civil rights -- Brazil; Human rights -- Brazil; Citizenship -- Brazil; Law reform -- Brazil; Ford Foundation Program development Brazil
- Reproductive Health and Population program: a progress report 1990-1992, 1992 Sept. (Reports 012335) (Box 607)
  Prepared for discussion at the September 1992 meeting of the Board of Trustees.
  Board of Trustees'Reproductive Health and Population
  Birth control -- Developing countries; Women's rights -- Developing countries; Women's health services -- Developing countries; Ford Foundation Reproductive Health and Population Program development
- Overview of program: Bangladesh (Reports 012336), 1992 (Box 607)
  Asia/Bangladesh;Board of Trustees
  Technical assistance -- Bangladesh; Endowments -- Bangladesh -- Evaluation; Ford Foundation
- Dispute resolution: directions for research and possible institutional mechanisms to support future research, 1991 (Reports 012337) (Box 607)
  Report is the result of interviews soliciting "views of a wide array of people interested in the field of dispute resolution (DR) to obtain advice regarding needed research in the field and appropriate vehicles to deliver support for this research" -p. 1
  Program Division/Office of the Vice President;Governance and Public Policy
  08300205
  96 leaves.
  Dispute resolution (Law) -- United States; National Institute for Dispute Resolution (U.S.) NIDR
- Resource generation for social change: new capacities and opportunities for Indian NGOs (Reports 012338), 1992 (Box 607)
  Report discusses the fund raising skills and capacity building needs of Indian non-governmental organizations (NGOs).
  Non-governmental organizations -- India; Philanthropy -- India
- Available and affordable liability insurance for non profit organizations, 1987 Oct. (Reports 012339) (Box 607)
  Report is the result of an assignment undertaken on behalf of an Ad Hoc Committee of the Ford Foundation. It discusses "whether there [are] any feasible and appropriate actions that might be supported by the Foundation to avoid a recurrence of the liabili
  13,11 leaves.
  Insurance, Liability -- United States; Nonprofit organizations -- United States -- Insurance; Ford Foundation. Program-Related Investments
- Review of the Community Fellows Program at Massachusetts Institute of Technology (Reports 012340), 1989 (Box 607)
  This report was prepared for Robert Curvin, director of the Foundation's Urban Poverty program, to assist him in reviewing a proposal from the Community Fellows Program at M.I.T.
  Civic leaders -- Scholarships, fellowships, etc.; Minorities -- Scholarships, fellowships, etc.; Community leadership -- United States; Massachusetts Institute of Technology. Community Fellows Program MIT/CFP
- Review of High/Scope Educational Research Foundation's proposal for the training of teacher trainers project (Reports 012341), 1987 (Box 607)
  Teachers -- Training of -- United States; High/Scope Educational Research Foundation
- A terminal program in business education: GCT (Reports 012342), 1962 (Box 607)
  Presents a strategy for the Foundation's terminal grant-making program in the business education-administration field.
  Business education -- Aims and objectives -- United States; Business schools -- Aims and objectives -- United States; Ford Foundation Economic Development and Administration Program development
- Final report on site visits to University of Massachusetts at Amherst; Wesleyan University; Stanford University (Reports 012344), 1989 (Box 607)
  Memorandum to Alison Bernstein, program officer, Education and Culture Program. Presents Candelaria's assessment of how successfully University of Massachusetts/Amherst, Wesleyan and Stanford are including the "New Scholarship" on women and minorities and
  16, 4 leaves.
  Education, Higher -- United States -- Curricula; Multicultural education -- United States; Educational equalization -- United States; Pluralism (Social sciences) -- United States; Women -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- United States; Minorities; University of Massachusetts at Amherst Curricula; Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.) Curricula; Stanford University Curricula; Ford Foundation. Race Relations/Campus Diversity Initiative
- Visit to Institute of Biotic Resources (INIREB), Jalapa, Mexico (Reports 012345-001), 1976 (Box 607)
  Natural resources; Environmental management; Ecosystem management; Agricultural ecology; Environmental protection
- The research program at SRI: Background, development and evaluation (Reports 012345-002), undated (Box 607)
- Environmental research and training in Egypt (Reports 012345-003), undated (Box 607)
- Lebanese National Council for Scientific Research, Environment program: Evaluation (Reports 012345-004), 1975 (Box 607)
- Middle east environment program(Visit to Beirut 9-12 (Reports 012345-005), 1975 (Box 607)
- Environment program of the National Council for Scientific Research, Lebanon (Reports 012345-006), 1974 (Box 607)
- Environment program: National Council for Scientific Research Lebanon (Reports 012345-007), undated (Box 607)
- The environment program of the National Council for Scientific Research in the Lebanon: Report of visit Dec.13-21 (Reports 012345-008), 1972 (Box 607)
- Visit to Beirut, March 13-18 (Reports 012345-009), 1972 (Box 607)
- Visit to Israel, February 5-9 (Reports 012345-010), 1977 (Box 607)
- Visit to the University of Aleppo, August 9-10 (Reports 012345-011), 1975 (Box 607)
- Visit to Tunisia, April 3 (Reports 012345-012), 1974 (Box 607)
- Visit to Kuwait: December 14-18 (Reports 012345-013), 1973 (Box 607)
- Environment research training project, Institut Pertanian Bogor, Indonesia (Reports 012345-014), 1975 (Box 607)
- Proposal for an environmental research training project on land and water resource development at Institut Pertanian Bogor (IPB) (Reports 012345-015), 1974 (Box 607)
- Visit to Indonesia, Thailand, India and Nepal, December 1974 (Reports 012345-016), 1975 (Box 607)
- An ecological review of the development of natural resource in India and Pakistan (Reports 012345-017), 1968 (Box 607)